Finding Aid for the Anna Ryder Dickey Collection Biomed.0213
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Books, 1901-1965; Series 3.
  - "Our national parks", by John Muir. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1902. (Folder 2)
    Author's autograph presentation copy, inscribed on upper free endpaper to Mrs. Ernest M. [Anna R.] Dickey, from Martinez, September 1902; photograph, annotated by Muir ("my Yosemite cabin"), pasted on flyleaf; portrait pasted on p. [1]
    Call Number: Biomed E 160 M896o 1902 Rare
  - "Stickeen", by John Muir. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1910, [c1909]. (Folder 3)
    Author's autograph presentation copy, inscribed in ink on upper free endpaper.
    Call Number: Biomed QL 795 D6 M896s 1910 Rare
  - "The Yosemite", by John Muir. New York: Century, 1912. (Folder 4)
    Author's autograph presentation copy, inscribed on upper free endpaper to Anna R. Dickey, May 1910.
    Call Number: Biomed F 868 Y6 M896y 1912 Rare
  - "The story of my boyhood and youth, with illustrations from sketches by the author", by John Muir. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1913. (Folder 5)
    "Ex libris Anna R. Dickey"; her inscription, dated 1913, on upper free endpaper.
    Call number: Biomed WZ 100 M896 1913 Rare
  - "Letters to a friend, written to Mrs. Ezra S. Carr, 1866-1879", by John Muir. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1915. (Folder 6)
    Call Number: Biomed PS 2447 M5 Z485 1915 Rare
  - "Alaska days with John Muir", by Samuel Hall Young. New York: Fleming H. Revell Co. [c1915]. (Folder 7)
    "Ex libris Anna R. Dickey"; inscription on upper free endpaper.
    Call Number: Biomed F 908 Y87a 1915 Rare
  - "The life and letters of John Muir" by William Frederic Badè. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1924. 2 vols. (Folder 8)
    Photographic portraits of Muir tipped on upper paste-down of each volume.
    Call Number: Biomed WZ 100 M896B 1924 Rare
  - "Son of the wilderness; the life of John Muir", by Linnie Marsh Wolfe. New York: A.A. Knopf, 1945. (Folder 9)
    "Ex libris Donald R. Dickey Memorial Library"; bookplate on upper paste-down; portrait of Muir pasted on upper free endpaper.
    Call Number: Biomed WZ 100 M896W 1945 Rare
  - "John Muir and the Sierra Club; the battle for Yosemite", by Holway R. Jones. San Francisco: Sierra Club, 1965. (Folder 10)
    Call Number: Biomed F 868 Y6 J71j 1965 Rare